[
    {
        "question": "What does PoP stand for?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) PoP stands for Post Office Protocol",
        "options": [
            "Pre Office Protocol",
            "Post Office Protocol",
            "Protocol of Post",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the port number of PoP?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The ports number of PoP is 110",
        "options": [
            "35",
            "43",
            "110",
            "25"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the number of layers in the OSI model?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) OSI model consists of 7 layers.",
        "options": [
            "2 layers",
            "4 layers",
            "7 layers",
            "9 layers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The full form of OSI is?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) OSI stands for Open system interconnection.",
        "options": [
            "Operating System interface",
            "Optical System interconnection",
            "Operating System Internet",
            "Open system interconnection"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the layer which provides service to the user.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Application layer provides service to the user.",
        "options": [
            "Session layer",
            "Application layer",
            "Presentation error",
            "Physical layer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a HUB?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) A HUB is a network device",
        "options": [
            "Software",
            "Computing device",
            "Network device",
            "Calculating device"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a set of rules define?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Protocol defines a set of rules.",
        "options": [
            "SMTP",
            "FTP",
            "IMAP",
            "Protocol"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following which is mainly used to host web site.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Web server is mainly used to host web site.",
        "options": [
            "Mail server",
            "Webserver",
            "Database server",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the full form of HTTP?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) HTTPS stands for HyperText Transfer Protocol",
        "options": [
            "HyperText Transfer Protocol",
            "HyperText Transfer Package",
            "Hyper Transfer Text Package",
            "Hyper Transfer Text Practice"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the protocol primarily used for browsing data.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) HTTP is used for browsing data.",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "TCP",
            "TFTP",
            "HTTP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the total versions of IP.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) IP has 2 versions, IPV4 and IPV6.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the first network which was based on TCP/IP protocol.",
        "answer": "Answer - A) ARPANET was the first network that was based on TCP/IP protocol.",
        "options": [
            "ARPANET",
            "HUB",
            "Ethernet Card",
            "Router"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following, which is the most common internet protocol.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) SMTP is the most commonly used internet protocol.",
        "options": [
            "PPP",
            "FTP",
            "TCP/IP",
            "SMTP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does TCP/IP stand for?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) TCP/IP stands for Transmission control protocol/Internet protocol.",
        "options": [
            "Telephone control protocol / Internet Protocol",
            "Transmission control protocol/Internet protocol",
            "Transmission control protocol/International protocol",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following layer isnâ€™t present in the TCP/IP model but is included in the OSI model?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) The TCP/IP model does not contain a session layer.",
        "options": [
            "Network layer",
            "Session layer",
            "Application layer",
            "Transport layer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the collection of the hyperlinked document on the internet known as?",
        "answer": "Answer - The collection of the hyperlinked document on the internet known as WWW.",
        "options": [
            "HTML",
            "Email",
            "WWW",
            "Internet"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the location of a resource on the internet given by?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) The location of a resource on the internet is given by URL",
        "options": [
            "Email",
            "IP",
            "Protocol",
            "URL"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the incorrect network topology,",
        "answer": "Answer - C) P2P is not network topology.",
        "options": [
            "Bus",
            "Star",
            "P2P",
            "Ring"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the port number of FTP.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) The port number of FTP is 21.",
        "options": [
            "23",
            "21",
            "110",
            "143"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length of the IPv4 address?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The length of the IPv4 address is 32 bits.",
        "options": [
            "8 bits",
            "16 bits",
            "32 bits",
            "128 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length of the IPv6 address?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) The length of the IPv6 address is 128 bits.",
        "options": [
            "8 bits",
            "16 bits",
            "32 bits",
            "128 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term used when the main server sends mail to another mail server?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) SMTP is the term used when the main server sends mail to another mail server.",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "SMTP",
            "TCP/IP",
            "MIME"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the port number of SMTP?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The port number of SMTP is 25.",
        "options": [
            "110",
            "143",
            "25",
            "99"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does MIME stand for?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) MIME stands for Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension.",
        "options": [
            "Multipurpose Internet Mail Extra",
            "Multi Internet Mail End",
            "Multipurpose Internet Mail Email",
            "Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does port number 143 refer to?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Port number 143 refers to IMAP.",
        "options": [
            "SMTP",
            "FTP",
            "IMAP",
            "POP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following the network device used to connect two dis-similar types of networks.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Gateway is used to connect two dis-similar types of networks.",
        "options": [
            "Switch",
            "Hub",
            "Bridge",
            "Gateway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the device used to boost up a weak signal.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Repeater is used to boost up a weak signal.",
        "options": [
            "Modem",
            "Repeater",
            "Switch",
            "Router"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does MAC stand for?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) MAC stands for Media Access Control.",
        "options": [
            "Media Access Control",
            "Mass Access Control",
            "Media Access Carriage",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length of the MAC address?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Length of MAC address is 48 bits.",
        "options": [
            "8 bits",
            "16 bits",
            "32 bits",
            "48 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to allocate and manage resources for a network?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Server is used to allocate and manage resources for a network.",
        "options": [
            "Bluetooth",
            "Server",
            "Node",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The arrangement where all data pass through a central computer is known as",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The arrangement where all data pass through a central computer is known as Star topology.",
        "options": [
            "Ring topology",
            "Mesh topology",
            "Star topology",
            "Bus topology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What of the following device is used in the network layer?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Router is used in the network layer.",
        "options": [
            "Application gateway",
            "Switch",
            "Router",
            "Repeaters"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify if the following statement is True or False: Network Interface Card(NIC) is an I/O device.",
        "answer": "Answer - A) NIC is an I/O device.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False",
            "Depends on usage",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is required to use a Simple Network Management System?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Rules are required to use a Simple Network Management System.",
        "options": [
            "Servers",
            "Protocols",
            "Rules",
            "IP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the major difference between SNMPv3 and SNMPv2.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) The major difference between SNMPv3 and SNMPv2 is Enhanced security.",
        "options": [
            "Classification",
            "Integration",
            "Management",
            "Enhanced security"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the network which extends a private network across a public network.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) VPN extends a private network across a public network.",
        "options": [
            "Storage Area network",
            "Virtual private network",
            "Enterprise Private network",
            "Local area network"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the layer which is responsible for data translating.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Presentation layer is used for data translating.",
        "options": [
            "Network",
            "Datalink",
            "Presentation",
            "Application"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the layer which determines the interface of the system with the user.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Application layer is used to determine the interface of the system with the user.",
        "options": [
            "Network",
            "Datalink",
            "Presentation",
            "Application"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following topology arrangements is a point-to-point line configuration?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above consists of a point-to-point line configuration.",
        "options": [
            "RIng",
            "Mesh",
            "Star",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the device which links two homogeneous packed broadcast local networks.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Bridge is used to link two homogeneous packed broadcast local networks.",
        "options": [
            "Hub",
            "Router",
            "Bridge",
            "Gateway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are parity bits used?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Parity bits are used to detect the error.",
        "options": [
            "To encrypt data",
            "To detect error",
            "To identify user",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following which belongs to class A.",
        "answer": "Answer - A)121.12.12.248 belongs to class A as the first octet value in the address lies between [0, 127].",
        "options": [
            "121.12.12.248",
            "128.12.12.248",
            "129.12.12.248",
            "130.12.12.248"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does LAN stand for?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) LAN stands for Local Area Network.",
        "options": [
            "Local Array Network",
            "Local Area Network",
            "Local Area Net",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Who keeps the private key in asymmetric key cryptography?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Receiver keeps the private key in asymmetric key cryptography.",
        "options": [
            "Sender",
            "Receiver",
            "Both Sender and Receiver",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Calculate the maximum efficiency of pure ALOHA at G = 0.5?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) The maximum efficiency of pure ALOHA is given by G * e^(-2G)         Here G = 0.5         So, 0.5 * e^(-2 * 0.5) = 0.5 * e = 18.4%",
        "options": [
            "16%",
            "1.89%",
            "18.4%",
            "18.999%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the switching method in which the message is divided into small packets.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) In packet switching message is divided into small packets.",
        "options": [
            "Virtual switching",
            "Packet switching",
            "Message switching",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a proxy server also known as?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) Proxy server is also known as Application-level gateway.",
        "options": [
            "Application-level gateway",
            "Proxy tools",
            "Application proxy",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following servers which allow LAN users to share data.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) File server allows LAN users to share data.",
        "options": [
            "Communication server",
            "Point server",
            "Data server",
            "File server"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct formula for the total vulnerable time value of pure ALOHA.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) The total vulnerable time value of pure ALOHA is 2*Tfr.",
        "options": [
            "Â½ Tfr",
            "Tfr",
            "2*Tfr",
            "4*Tfr"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose among the following which is a bit-oriented protocol.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) HDLC or High-level link control is a bit-oriented protocol that is used to transmit info from one network to another.",
        "options": [
            "SSL",
            "HDLC",
            "HTTP",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    }
]